喜欢吗?
You like that?
嗯...我不知道
Uh...I don't know.
想看臀部表演?
You want me to use my butt again?
我不记得怎么到这里的
I don't know how I got here.
我喝了多少酒?
How many drinks did I have?
你的苏格兰酒还没有送过来
Your scotch hasn't even arrived yet.
也就是我来之前就已经醉了
Means I was drunk when I got here.
8点50
8:50.
我记得我在工作
I remember being at work.
我失去了四个小时的记忆
I've lost at least four hours.
说五个单词
Say five words.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
你只说了四个单词
That's four words.
诊断记忆损伤的标准测试是五个随机单词
The accepted diagnostic test for global/memory impairment is five random words.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
我也想知道
I'M...trying to find that out.
说出五种动物
Give me five animals.
猫 鸟 猴子
Um...cat,bird,monkey.
犀牛
Rhino.
金鱼
Goldfish.
猴子 犀牛...
Monkey. Rhino...
要么是我醉得一塌糊涂...
either I'm massively drunk...
你在流血
oh,you're bleeding.
或者这是别人的血
Or it's someone else's blood.
你看见伤口了吗?
Do you see a wound?
有多大?
How bad is it?
挺大
It's all over.
我脑震荡了
I have a concussion.
倒退性失忆
Retrograde amnesia.
没有钥匙 没有手机
No keys,no phone.
我被打劫了
I've been mugged.
不 你没有
No,you haven't.
你给了我20元
You already gave me a 20.
你跳够20元了?
Did you earn it?
还没
Not yet.
有人要死了
Someone is going to die.
Kenny!
不是你
Not you.
我看见些事情
I saw something.
一个症兆
A symptom.
有人要死了 除非让我找到他们
Someone is going to/die unless I find them.
谁?
Who?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
找零送你了
Keep the change.
我看见有人死了
I saw somebody dying.
你目睹了30个人飞向玻璃和金属
you saw 30 people flying/into glass and metal.
我在撞车前看见了症兆
I saw a symptom before the crash.
你有脑震荡 你不知道你看见了什么
You're concussed-- you/don't know what you saw,
也不知道是何时看见的
and you don't know when you saw it.
一周之前/你还注意到了肥皂剧男星的症状
A week ago,you noticed/a symptom in a soap star.
论据错误
Bad argument.
因为我判断正确
Since I was right about that.
但是你的大脑却以为就发生在昨天
But your brain obviously/thinks it happened last night.
思维混乱
Wires are crossed.
快好了
That's all of it.
再来几针 脑子就掉不出来了
A few stitches will/hold your brain in place.
嘿 脑袋别乱晃/除非你想我把鼻子和眼睛缝在一起
Hey,hold your head still,unless you/want me to sew your nose onto your eye.
我为什么会坐公共汽车?
Why was I taking the bus?
因为你喝醉了
Because you were drunk.
如果是因为我看见了某人 尾随他/从普林斯顿上了车?
What if I saw someone and I followed/them on from...somewhere in princeton?
你还好吧?
You okay?
好极了
Perfect.
呃...你
Uh...uh... you.
问询这里每个病人的病史
Get histories from everyone in here.
你是不是忘了他的名字?
Did you just forget his name?
没有
No.
女同性恋
Lesbian.
看看这个公共汽车上的伤员/有没有去别的医院
Find out if anybody on that bus/was taken to other hospitals.
他忘了我的名字
He just forgot mine.
没有忘 13号
No,thirteen.
我只是想叫你同性恋
I just wanted to call you a lesbian.
我不是同性恋
I'm not a lesbian.
我四舍五入
I was rounding up.
根据50%的表现
From 50%.
找到我的手杖和摩托车
Find my cane and motorcycle.
找出我昨晚都去过哪些地方
Figure out where I went last night.
你的手杖和摩托车在哪?
Where's your cane and motorcycle?
你昨晚都去哪了?
And where'd you go last night?
你相信我的话?
You gonna trust me?
我从不说真话
I lie about everything.
今晚你要留院观察
you're staying the night.
需要监控你大脑肿胀的情况
We need to monitor/your brain for swelling.
会肿多大呢?
How much bigger could it get?
你不觉得这...有点奇怪吗
You don't think it's... a little weird
在严重撞车事故的同时/你看到了神秘的症状
that there is both a giant crash and a/simultaneous,mysterious symptom sighting?
如果不是巧合呢?
What if it's not a coincidence?
你是说上帝从天空中伸出手来玩弄你?
You mean like the hand of god/reaching down and screwing with you?
那个...
That.
或者是症状导致了撞车事故
Or the symptom caused the crash.
有没有看见穿公交司机制服的人?
You see anybody in a/bus driver's uniform?
就是这里
Right here.
公共汽车司机脖子上的紫斑
Purpura on lalph klamden's neck.
白血病的特征
Indicative of leukemia.
导致大脑出血 事故发生
It caused the bleed in the/brain,hence the accident...
说明他系了安全带
indicative of wearing a seatbelt.
只是一条瘀痕
It's just a bruise.
我有白血病?
I have leukemia?
不 我们刚排除了那个
No. We just ruled that out.
注意听
Pay attention.
你可能痉挛了
you probably had a seizure.
我没有痉挛
I didn't have a seizure.
我被垃圾车撞了
I got hit by a garbage truck.
就是痉挛才开车失控撞上去的
Which you drove into/while you were seizing.
你看到驾驶员显示出痉挛的初期征兆
You saw the bus driver exhibiting/the initial stages of a seizure
却懒得提醒他停车?
and didn't bother/telling him to pull over?
嘿!
Hey!
除非我说可以走 谁都不许离开
Nobody leaves here until I/say they can be discharged.
- 她说我--/- 她是我吗?
- She said I was--/- is she me?
你在发烧
You have a fever.
不 我很好
No. I'm fine.
华氏98.6度(摄氏37度)
98.6.
他得留下来
I need him to stay.
脉搏正常
pulse is normal.
血压正常
Bp's normal.
一切都正常
Everything's normal.
我只是车祸后颈部僵直
I just have a stiff neck from the crash.
颈部僵直
A stiff neck.
这人有脑膜炎
This man has meningitis.
我们得隔离整个急诊区
We need to quarantine the whole E.R.
只有完成了全身体检之后才能离开
No one leaves here until/their full workup is complete.
你下午5:23离开这里的
you left here at 5:23 P.M.
摩托车没能载你回到家
Your motorcycle never made it home.
那就解释了我忘掉的四小时中的十秒钟
Well...that covers ten seconds out/of the four hours I can't remember.
你们还查了哪里?
Where else did you look?
我们把所有伤患都列了个清单
We did pull up a list/of all the injuries.
一共有22人/伤情从骨盆骨折到右脚折断不等
22 victims were brought here,injuries ranging/from a broken pelvis to a severed right foot.
还有八个人被送往普林斯顿综合医院
the other eight were taken/over to princeton general.
如果有脸部照片和简历的话/就更有帮助了
It would be helpful if these/came with head shots and resumes.
二十出头的女性无名氏
20-something-year-old/jane doe.
肾部受创 腿部伤口
Kidney contusion,laceration on her leg.
两种都是汽车高速骤停的可能并发症
Both of which are expected complications when/someone goes from 60 to 0 in no seconds flat.
最奇特的病症也就是脾脏破裂了
The weirdest thing we've/got is a ruptured spleen.
好吧 新计划
Okay. New plan.
列出从这里到车祸现场所有酒吧清单
We make a list of all the bars/between here and the crash site.
查清我去了哪间 然后去那儿--
We find out where/I went,we go there--
马上办
on it.
你们不打算照办是吧?
You're not gonna do anything,are you?
我们去急诊室干我们该干的
We're gonna go to the/E.R. And do our jobs.
因为我的失忆 有人正在濒死边缘—
Someone is dying because/I can't remember—
你想起来了可以呼我们
when you remember,you can page us.
从这儿到你记忆的捷径
The shortest distance/between here and your memory
是穿过你的前额皮质
is straight through/your prefrontal cortex.
我们只要进入它就行了
All we have to do is access it.
好主意
Great idea.
我会建好巨型潜水艇
I'll build the giant submarine.
你去准备小人(指电影"神奇旅程"/ 人缩小乘潜水艇进入大脑摧毁血块)
You get the miniaturization gizmo.
医学催眠可以让大脑处于/二级δ脑电波状态
Medical hypnosis can bring the/brain to a class ii theta state,
增强注意力并修补记忆
increasing focus and memory retrieval.
你不会让我跳小鸡舞吧?
You're not gonna make me do/the chicken dance,are you?
外科肯定有人是受过训练的
Someone in the surgical/department must be trained.
放松
Just relax.
别去想任何事
Keep letting go of/any intrusive thoughts.
你在漫画书背面看到催眠术广告去学的?
So what,you saw an ad in/the back of a comic book?
我曾在墨尔本轮值干过这个
I did a rotation in melbourne.
注意力集中到你呼吸的声音上
Focus on the sound of your breath.
你在折磨一个已经伤痕累累的大脑
You're taxing an already injured brain.
就像让他扭伤脚踝后多走路一样
It's like telling him to walk/it off after a broken ankle.
Wilson 你说够了
Wilson is done talking now.
想象那辆巴士
Visualize the bus.
它的形状 气息
The way it looked,the way it smelled.
车上的人
The people on it.
他们的样子
What they look like.
这完全是浪费--
This is a waste of--
时间
time.
酷
Cool.
注意细节
Focus on the details.
巴士是空的
Bus is empty.
这真在起作用?
Is this really working?
只是... 集中注意力
Just... focus.
别去想其它
Clear your mind.
只回想你的感受
Think back to how you felt.
看到的细节
Details you saw.
我看不见窗外
I can't see out the windows.
但我能看到你们
And I can see you guys.
离车祸越远的记忆应该越清晰
Memories further from the/incident should be clearer.
上巴士之前你在哪儿?
Where were you before/you got on the bus?
为什么会在下午五点醉醺醺的/还是独自一人?
why'd you get so drunk at/5:00 in the afternoon,alone?
这也需要理由?
I need a reason?
老天 我讨厌"啤酒"牌啤酒
God,I hate"beer" brand beer.
当他被催眠时能撒谎吗?
When he's hypnotized,can he lie?
- 他--/- 我可能犯错
- He--/- I can be mistaken.
但在催眠状态我不可能撒谎
I can't actually lie under hypnosis.
- 他在撒谎?/- 没有
- Is he lying?/- No.
你在逃避什么?
What are you running away from?
当我喝酒却没叫你时 我在逃避什么?
When I'm drinking without/you,what am I running away from?
总是那些不可估量因素之一
One of those imponderables.
你能把不安全感抛开/先找到那个病人再说吗?
Can you hold off on your insecurities/until we find this patient?
在酒吧你看到什么人了没?
Do you see anyone in the bar?
面目不清的一群人
I see a faceless crowd.
我怎么集中注意力?
How do I focus?
跟我说点什么让我集中注意力
Say something to make me focus.
他很担心你
he's concerned about you.
那为什么意味着他缺乏安全感?
Why does that mean he's insecure?
把你的...女朋友弄出去
Get your...girlfriend outta here.
这是个合情合理的问题
It's a legit question.
Amber在那儿? 你在脑子里看到Amber了?
amber's there? You've/got amber in your head?
你把她弄进我脑子里的
You put her in my head.
我连在潜意识里跟你谈谈/她都得在一边搅和
I can't even have a conversation with youin/my subconscious without her tagging along.
她最好衣衫整齐
She'd better have her clothes on.
很不幸
Unfortunately.
我不是故意要说出声的
I didn't mean to say that out loud.
说什么?
Say what out loud?
我并没有说出声来
I didn't say it out loud.
没事
nothing.
那儿到底怎么了?
What's going on in there?
要是我不能撒谎的话 这两人得出去
If I can't lie,I need/these two outta here.
就当Wilson和Amber不存在 好吗?
Let's just...ignore wilson and/amber from now on,shall we?
我希望--
I wish it were that--
墨尔本的项目还真有一套
that's some program they got/down there in melbourne.
干杯
Cheers.
我记得酒保
I remember the bartender.
很好
good.
现在你正进入自己的颞叶
Now you're accessing your temporal lobe.
那酒保有什么奇怪的症状吗?
Does the bartender have any odd symptoms?
没有 他看起来挺好
No. He seems fine.
这里有人生病了吗?
Anybody here sick?
有人上了巴士吗?
Anyone here taking the bus?
你啊
You are.
因为你拿走了我的钥匙
Because you took my keys.
好 这很好
good. This is good.
现在我们可以重新追踪你的行程了
Now we can retrace your steps.
我们回到巴士上
Let's go back to the bus.
你面前是什么?
What's in front of you?
乘客
Passengers.
他们有...什么特别的吗?
Anything...special about them?
一个想成为情绪摇滚吉他英雄的人
Some emo guitar hero wanna be.
你注意到了他 为什么?
You're focusing on him. Why?
因为挖鼻孔可能是鼻腔内膜炎
Because nose picking/could mean nasal peritis.
他要死了
He's dying.
你喜欢挖鼻孔?
You a nose picker?
我非得回答吗--
Do I have to answer--
要不是 你早就回答了
if the answer was/no,you'd have answered.
头向后仰
Tilt your head back.
他没事
He's fine.
他连脑膜炎都没有
He doesn't even have meningitis.
和其他人一样/我们却得给他们打脑膜炎预防针
Just like everybody else we've had/to give meningitis shots to.
你可以走了
You can go.
你有脑瘤
You have a brain tumor.
你在开玩笑对吧?
You're kidding,right?
我要在开玩笑 就穿跟你一样的衣服了
If I was kidding,I'd/be dressed like you.
你没事
You're fine.
护士会签字让你走的
A nurse will sign you out.
回家 找点乐子 放松放松
Go home. Have fun. Relax.
我说不定就是个神经病
I'm probably just a nut case.
头向后仰
Tilt your head back.
你可以拿好东西走了
You can get your things and go.
你得休息
You need to rest.
我收你入院
I'm admitting you.
我没法起身
I can't get up.
腿动不了
I can't move my legs.
腿的问题不是最严重的
Your legs are not your biggest problem.
最严重的是/我不知道你最严重的问题是什么
Your biggest problem is I don't/know what your biggest problem is.
我们知道是谁了 但不知道是什么
so we have the who but not the what.
只有一个症状-- 突发瘫痪
we've only got one symptom to/go on-- sudden onset paralysis.
我们实际上有两个症状
We actually have two symptoms.
只记得一个
only one that we remember.
你跟他做了全身体检--发现什么了?
you did a full workup on the/guy--did you find anything?
CT排除了硬脑膜下血肿 中风/或蛛网膜下出血
ct ruled out subdural hematoma,stroke,or/subarachnoid hemorrhage.
符合格林-巴利综合症
Guillain-barre fits.
正在琢磨格林-巴利综合症是什么样子
Just trying to figure out what/guillain-barre looks like.
你不能因为跟你也许看到的不相符/就排除一切可能
you can't just eliminate everything because/it doesn't match what you might have seen.
要是因为它不符合我可能看到的呢?
How 'bout because it doesn't/match what I could have seen?
难道格林-巴利综合症没有外部身体特征
Guillain-barre has no/external physical manifestations.
每种病都有外部身体特征
Everything has some/external physical manifestations.
你太偏执的话 总能联想到
And you're obsessive/enough to notice any of them,
就根本没有我们能排除的
which means there's/nothing we can rule out.
血白细胞计数增高
Elevated white count.
可能是横贯性脊髓炎--
Makes transverse/myelitis--
是啊 开巴士的时候突然瘫痪
yeah,sudden paralysis while/driving a bus.
这的确是只有天才才会/注意到的细微线索
That's the sort of subtle clue that/only a genius would have noticed.
你确定你没事?
Are you sure you're feeling okay?
你去哪儿?
where are you going?
去闻巴士 很明显
To smell a bus. Obviously.
是啊
Yeah.
我开始给他上抗生素/以防他真是横贯性脊髓炎
I'll,uh,start him on antibiotics/in case it's transverse myelitis.
你们去...闻一闻城市公交车
You guys go...sniff a city bus.
你为什么要闻乘客们的衣服?
Why are you smelling the/passengers' clothes?
嗅觉是触发记忆的最好方式
Smell is the most/powerful evokerater of memory.
我得回到那辆巴士上
I need to get back on that bus.
好吧 但你为什么要吃那么多维可丁?
Okay. So why are/you taking so much vicodin?
要是Cuddy问起来 就说消除疼痛/能有助于专注于记忆
If cuddy asks,blocking the/pain helps focus the memory.
你弄破了头 应该休息
You split your head/open. You should rest.
有发现吗?
Anything?
暗示... 爆炸的巴士
Hint of... exploded bus.
House 你四十秒钟内服下4颗维可丁
house,that's four vicodin in 40 seconds.
- 照这样下去--/- 祝我好运
- At this rate--/- wish me luck.
我现在是...兰博状态了
I'm going in...rambo style.
House 你到底是觉得这能有用/还是你药磕多了?
house,do you think this is gonna/work,or are you just stoned?
显然都是
Both,apparently.
你错了
you're wrong.
这没什么作用
It's not working.
所以你是说我不在这儿
So you're saying I'm not here.
要是真实记忆 你就该是跛的/也不会跟我说话了
If it was a real memory,you'd be/limping,and you wouldn't be talking to me.
我很显然只是个幻觉
I'm obviously a hallucination.
好吧 所以我维可丁吃多了点
Okay. So I went a/littleheavy on the vicodin.
但愿如此
Better hope so.
因为如果不是那样... 就说明你在脑出血
'Cause otherwise... means/your brain's bleeding.
我们俩都在我脑子里
We're both in my head.
我想总有一个会注意到流血的
I think one of us would/have noticed the blood.
你为什么还没去做脑CT?
Why haven't you had a head ct yet?
你到底要我治谁 你还是我?
Who do you want me to treat,me or you?
你痉挛了吗?
Did you have a seizure?
蠢问题
Dumb question.
痉挛时大脑一片混乱 形成不了记忆
The brain's too fried during/a seizure to form memories.
蠢答案
Dumb answer.
我又没问你
I wasn't asking you.
我在问我自己
I was asking me.
你已经证明你不存在了
You've already proven that/you're not here.
我头很疼
I'm getting a headache.
这是条线索?
Is that a clue?
再说一遍...我不存在
Again...I'm not here.
你在头疼
You're etting a headache.
别跟幻觉吵架 赶紧去治治
Stop arguing with a hallucination/and get some treatment.
他不能
he can'T.
幻觉是你受创的大脑在试图解决难题
The hallucination is your messed up/brain's way of reasoning out a problem.
你不在巴士上
You weren't on the bus.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
这双鞋值500块
$500 shoes.
不可能上穿越普林斯顿的巴士
Not on the princeton cross-town.
我在此地 一定有别的原因
Must be another reason why I'm here.
是的
Yes.
你想要告诉我什么?
What do you have to tell me?
我在跟巴士上的乘客说话!
I was talking to the/passengers on the bus!
你正在产生幻觉
You were hallucinating.
你得去做核磁共振
You're getting an mri.
别乱动
Stop fidgeting.
要是还没有找到出血点/就不可能是—
If you haven't found the/bleed yet,it can't be—
颞叶控制短时记忆的部分/有水肿和局部肿胀
there's edema and localized swelling in the section/of the temporal lobe that controls short-term memory.
还有 阴茎状的外皮显示"可悲"
Also,the penis-size cortex/is set to "pathetic."
你有什么没大声说出来?
What didn't you say out loud?
很少
Very little.
你被催眠时在跟Amber说话
When you were under hypnosis,you/were talking to amber.
我想看她裸体
I wanted to see her naked.
说真的 你在隐瞒什么?
Seriously,what were you hiding?
我想看她裸体
I wanna see her naked.
你想看每个人裸体
You wanna see everyone naked.
这有什么好隐瞒?
Why would you hide that?
有些人会不爽别人性幻想他女朋友
Some guys get upset when you/objectify their girlfriends.
但如果你不介意 我有个数码摄像机/我们可以—
But if you're okay,I've got a/digital video camera,so we could—
你对我女友 像对地球上所有女人一样/为什么我会不爽?
why would I be upset that you're treating my girlfriend/like you treat every other woman on the planet?
除非...你并没有那样
Unless...you're not.
除非更深刻
Unless it's deeper than that.
你并没有对她性幻想
You weren't objectifying her.
相信我
Trust me.
我想对你女朋友做非常肮脏下流的事
I wanna do some very nasty,demeaning/stuff to your girlfriend.
你对她有感觉
You have feelings for her.
这很糟糕
This is bad.
颞骨纵骨折
It's a longitudinal fracture/of the temporal bone.
我撞到头了
I banged my head.
这可不是擦破块皮那么简单
This isn't just a boo-boo.
知道那家伙得什么病后/我会去休息的
I'll rest once I figure/out what's wrong with this guy.
为什么? 这个人有什么特别?
Why? Why this guy?
你想要那些病症稀奇古怪/无法确诊的病人
You want patients/with weird,undiagnosed symptoms,
你桌上每天早上都躺着5份那样的病例
you get five files like/that on your desk every morning.
你从没为了他们拼过老命
You'd never risk your life for them.
他有什么特别的 让你去当蝙蝠侠?
Why is this guy so special/that you've become batman?
我不知道
I don't know.
也许是因为你撞破了头/令你性情大变了
maybe it's because you have a/cracked skull and you're not yourself.
回家睡觉去吧
Go home, go to sleep
我能站起来了
my legs are holding.
好的 现在把重心移到右腿上来
Good. Now put all/yourweight on your right leg.
抗生素起作用了 是横贯性脊髓炎
The antibiotics are working. It's tm.
现在是凌晨2点
it's 2:00 in the morning.
你该在家好好待着/休养你那摔到歇菜的脑子
You should be home,resting/what's left of your bruised brain.
好得太快了
Recovery's too fast.
他有好转说明我们错了?
The fact that he's getting better/is evidence that we're wrong?
我要坐一下
I need to sit.
现在你觉得恢复够慢了吧?
Recovery slow enough for you now?
哦...胃痛!
Oh...it's my stomach!
这说明不是横贯性脊髓炎
Which means it's not transverse myelitis.
发作迅速 可能是穿孔性溃疡
Rapid onset--could/be a perforated ulcer.
但解释不了肢体麻痹
Wouldn't explain the paralysis.
阿狄森综合征
Addison's.
肿瘤引起的
From a tumor.
可能是我看到他眼皮耷拉了
It's possible I saw his eyelids droop.
我们都把他头扫描5回了
We've scanned his head five times.
你在流血
You're bleeding.
有种意外叫做"撞车"
Little thing called a bus crash.
只是头皮裂伤
It's just a scalp laceration.
可能隐藏在他视交叉之下
Could be hidden in his optic chiasm.
是从你耳朵里流出来的
It's coming from your ear.
你觉得是好事吗?
Think that's a good thing?
但那应该会影响到他的视力
But that would/have affected his eyesight.
我要去洗个澡
I need to take a bath.
幻觉和气味有点用 是吧?
hallucinations and smells/were kind of working right?
干嘛要洗澡?
Why the bath?
催眠让我想到了个爱挖鼻孔的
Hypnosis gave me a nose picker.
气味令我产生幻觉
Smells set off hallucinations.
感觉剥夺会令大脑进入α-δ脑电波状态
Sensory deprivation should get/the brain into an alpha-theta phase.
看过"变形博士"吗?
Didn't you see Altered States?
那片子上映时我还没出生呢
I don't think I was even born when that movie was on
你这年纪当医生可真够年轻的
you are too young to be a doctor
那片子是1980年上映的
That movie was on in 1980
那是28年前的事了
That was 28 years ago
别扯了 闭嘴
No, it wasn't. shut up
你是不是不记得今年是哪年了?
Did you just forget what year it is?
不 我只是想起我有多大了
No, I just remembered how old I am
给我点时间去换换脑子
I need to give my brain time to transition
我好跟同周公一起共赴淫诗艳友
so I can embrace my inner monkey
也许我不会那么做
maybe I don't
给我点毒扁豆碱 能越过血脑屏障
give me some physostigmine/it crosses the blood brain barrier
那玩意儿跟神经毒气一样 会令你心跳骤停/你好去西天当佛祖了
and act like nerve gas, stop your heart. You'll go to heaven and be omniscient
你想得美 那是不可能的
good idea, not gonna happen
别轻举妄动
don't do anything
即使我跑出来 吃了头山羊/被警察击毙了
Even if I escape, eat a goat, get shot by police
我那时还没出生 我听不明白那时的笑话
Wasn't born yet means I won't be entertained by further reference
我不知道你还搭公车的
I didn't know you rode the bus.
我都在喝得醉醺醺后驾车回家的
I used to drive home after getting drunk.
但有些妈妈很抓狂
But some mothers got mad-D.
你在这儿干嘛?
what're you doing here?
你跟我一起在车上?
you were on the bus for me
我想这大概不是你的记忆
I guess this is the memory
这是太虚梦境
This is a fantasy.
是梦境的话 你就会穿成...这样
If it's a fantasy,you'd/be wearing...this.
你确信你的病人快死了/还把时间花在香艳梦境里?
You're convinced your patient is dying,and/you wanna waste your time with a sex fantasy?
别怪我
Don't blame me.
要怪去怪男人吧
Blame my gender.
我不是来满足你那嗜好的
Well,I'm not here to indulge that.
我是来帮你搞清楚/你到底看到什么症状的
I'm here to help you figure/out what symptom you saw.
你的病人在开公交/所以你能看到只有...
Your patient was driving the/bus,so all you could see--
你为什么不双管齐下呢?
why can't you do both?
你的病人在开车
Your patient was driving the bus
你能看到的就是他坐着 面向前方
so all you could see was him sitting/down, most likely facing forward.
从后面看 我看到他的耳垂在晃动/或者头在轻轻摇摆
From behind,I saw his earlobes/wiggling or his head bobbing.
这我可看不到
But not that.
有可能是主动脉瓣闭锁不全
Could indicate aortic insufficiency.
马方氏综合征
Marfan's syndrome.
或者是梅毒
Or syphilis.
要是他的耳垂是下垂呢?
What if his earlobes were just drooping?
埃-丹二氏病?/(皮肤弹性过度症)
Ehlers-danlos?
或者是皮肤松垂症
Or cutis laxa.
在成年人身上并不致命
It's not fatal in adults.
没错 他是成人了 说得好
Yeah. He's an adult. Very good point.
继续
Keep going.
我让你分神了
I'm distracting you.
不!
no!
继续跳啊 女人!
Dance,woman!
你更愿意诊断病情
You'd rather be diagnosing.
我在喊 "不"
I screamed "no."
你自己的潜意识无视你的呼声
And your own subconscious ignored you.
因为你更愿意想象去找出病症
Because you'd rather/fantasize about finding symptoms.
可不妙啊
How screwed up is that?
嘿 看这边
hey. Over here.
还记得我吗?
Remember me?
我是那个病人
I'm the sick guy.
说说我都看到什么了
tell me what I saw.
我耳朵滴血了吗?
Was the blood dripping from my ear?
没道理
That doesn't make sense.
因为你的衬衫没滴到血
'Cause your shirt wasn't stained.
滴血的是我
And because that was me.
我可能是有点单侧抽搐/表现出亨廷顿舞蹈病的早期症状
I could have had a subtle hemiballismus,indicating/the early stages of huntington'S.
亨廷顿舞蹈病解释不了腹痛
Huntington's wouldn't explain/the abdominal pain.
是13号让我们联想到亨廷顿舞蹈病
It's only on the table/because we're thinking of thirteen.
脚步拖曳表明可能是帕金森
A shuffling gait could/suggest parkinson'S.
你坐着 我可观察不到脚步拖曳
Except there's no such/thing as shuffling sitting.
他扶老太太上台阶时走路了
he moved when he helped/the old lady up the steps.
你是谁?
Who are you?
我是一切的解答
I'm the answer.
看
Look.
看什么?
At what?
看这儿
here.
你说得对
You were right.
把他扶起来
Help him up.
我知道了 是帕金森
I got it. It's parkinson's.
House 你的耳朵
House,your ear.
给他用左旋多巴
Start him on levodopa.
你该坐下来
You should sit down.
House!
house!
从我眼前拿开
Get that out of my face.
欢迎回归人间
Welcome back.
我是Dickerson护士
I'm nurse dickerson.
我用不着知道你叫啥
I don't need your name.
鉴于你足以融掉我视网膜的高超技艺/我已经猜出你的职业了
And I got your profession from your/super-competent technique of melting my retinas.
语言能力似乎没有缺失
Verbal faculties seem to be intact.
你还记得自己昏过去吗?
Do you remember passing out?
我记得我吐Cuddy鞋上了
I remember puking on cuddy's shoes.
没错
Yeah.
颅骨骨折是很痛
Skull fractures tend to hurt.
你要是不把我的止痛药都收走/我可没这么痛
It would hurt a lot less if you/didn't swipe my pain pills.
Cuddy大夫的指示
Dr. Cuddy's orders.
希望我控制用药量...
Wants me to/regulate the amount--
等一下 你还带了警卫?
wait a second. You brought muscle?
Cuddy大夫的指示
Dr. Cuddy's orders.
说明我错了
Means I was wrong.
病人得的不是帕金森
My patient doesn't have parkinson's.
Cuddy知道那是唯一能让我抛下/止痛药 色情录像和你的原因
Cuddy knows that's the only reason I wouldn't want/to stay here with my pain pills,porn,and you forever.
呕吐说明你大脑损伤的更严重了
Vomiting means your brain/injury is getting worse.
House的颅骨骨折扩展到耳道了
house's skull fracture extends/all the way down to his ear canal.
House被人看护着
House is being looked after.
我们的病人有黄疸 低白蛋白 没有确诊
Our other patient has jaundice,low/albumin,and no diagnosis.
威尔逊氏病
Wilson's disease.
谢谢 但威尔逊氏病解释不了..
thank you. But wilson's/wouldn't explain-
- Foreman/- 怎么排除掉帕金森的?
- Foreman./- How did you eliminate parkinson's?
化验结果证实/腹痛是由于肝脏衰竭引起的
The tests confirmed the abdominal/pain was caused by liver failure.
我假设你已经排除了肝炎和威尔逊氏病
I assume you've already/ruled out hepatitis and wilson's.
你应该躺床上休息
You should really be resting.
给他5分钟让他说
Give him five minutes.
头脑风暴不会让他脑子当机的
Brainstorming a few possibilities/isn't going to explode his brain.
她要是错了的话/这通电话就更激动人心了
And if she's wrong,that makes this/phone call that much more exciting.
肝纤维化呢?
What about hepatic fibrosis?
不可能...他的碱性磷酸酶为正常水平
Can't be--his alkphos was normal.
可能是甲亢伴周期性瘫痪
Could be thyrotoxic periodic paralysis.
我有强调过只能说有意义的诊断吗?
Did I mention this/diagnosis needs to make sense?
这怎么就没意义了?
why doesn't it make sense?
公交司机是亚洲人 钾含量偏低
Bus driver's asian,his/potassium slightly low.
要是他在开车过程中瘫痪了
If he got paralyzed while/driving the bus,
你不觉得我该在下一站下了吗?
don't you think I would/have gotten off at the next stop?
如果那车没跟辆SUV呈90度相撞的话
not if the next stop was at/a 90-degree angle into an suv.
公交车可以减速的 我会注意...
The bus would have/slowed. I would have noti--
电话打完了
phone call's over.
TPP(甲亢伴周期性瘫痪)的症状完全吻合
Tpp has all the confirmed symptoms.
检测下没坏处
There's no downside to testing.
遗传检测太慢了...
Genetic testis/too slow--
去做百吉饼测试!
run the bagel test!
要检测出结果 我还得吃多少个百吉饼?
How many more bagels do I/have to eat for this to work?
高碳水化合物食品加上运动/是最快确证TPP的方法
High carbs plus exercise is/the quickest way to confirm tpp.
我这样已经有半小时了
I been on this for half an hour.
我不会再倒下去的
I'm not gonna collapse again.
加快速度
Up the speed.
继续吃
Keep eating.
喂?
Yeah?
加碳马拉松没用是吧
so the carbo-loading/marathon isn't working.
别探头探脑东张西望
Stop looking around suspiciously.
回答你接下来的2个问题/不 我不在那里
To answer your next two/questions,no,I am not there,
是的 你被摸透了
and yes,you are completely predictable.
检测有用的话 你们会给我电话/让我赢弱的大脑喘口气了
If the test had worked,you would have/called to put my delicate brain at ease.
跟你说了别锁门
I told you not to lock the door.
在擦了
Still wiping.
把电话放到司机嘴边
Put the phone upto bus driver's grill.
你在跟谁说话?
Who are you talking to?
我的结肠
My large colon.
TPP的症状跟病人现在大口喘粗气不符
Tpp is not consistent with/your patient's labored breathing.
病人喘粗气是因为/他在跑步机上走了30分钟了
Patient has labored breathing because he's/been on a treadmill for the last 30 minutes.
你是不是把我手机拿走了?
Did you take my cell phone?
我的结肠拿的
My large colon did.
我正跟它协商 拿回手机
I'm negotiating its release.
帮我一把
help.
怎么了?
What's happening?
测试奏效了
the test worked.
他倒了
He collapsed.
你们说对了一半
you're half right.
他在喘气吧?
He's wheezing,isn't he?
是的
Yeah.
不动胸大肌 人没法喘气
Can't wheeze without moving/your chest muscles.
不是TPP
This isn't tpp.
那到底是什么病?
Then what is it?
我咋知道? 我又不在那儿!
How am I supposed to/know? I'm not there!
右心室负荷过重 仍没供氧
Right heart strain. He's/still not oxygenating.
肯定是肺栓塞了
Must be a pulmonary embolism.
那怎么不来针tPA?/(tPA:纤溶酶原激活剂)
So why haven't you pushed a vial of tpa?
你放他回来了?
you let him back in?
我请他回来的
I asked him back in.
到头来我还得耐着性子/教训你们这些白痴
At the tail end of me patiently/explaining how you idiots were idiots—
我们10分钟前刚给他上过tPA
we pushed tpa ten minutes ago.
说明不是血块
That means it's not a clot.
肯定是血块...他如果气管卡进了百吉饼/ 我做超声时该看得到
has to be a clot-- if he had a bagel stuck/in his windpipe,I'd have seen it on the echo.
把他推到手术室去 把东西吸出来
Get him to the O.R.To suck it out.
肯定插管没插好
Must have just screwed up the intubation.
密封没问题
Seal's good.
是血块 House
It's a clot,house.
慢着 慢着
Wait,wait,wait.
看看他的牙
Look at his teeth.
他新做的烤瓷牙
He's got shiny new caps.
他新近做过牙科手术
He's had recent dental surgery.
你可以在推往手术室的路上/跟我们说这有何相干
You can tell us what that means/while we're rolling him to the O.R.
House!
house!
拿支注射器
Oh.Get a syringe.
我找你来不是让你来造反的
I didn't bring you back here/so you could stage a coup.
听我说
listen to me.
牙医的气钻往他牙龈里打了个气泡
Dental air drill pushed an/air bubble into his gums.
他开车时 气泡移位了
Dislodged while he's driving.
使他四肢抖动
Caused a myoclonic jerk.
我看见的正是这事
That's what I must have seen.
然后攻击了他的脊椎 肝脏/现在到了肺
Then it hit his spine,his/liver,now his lungs.
Hadley大夫 把门打开!
Dr. Hadley,open the door!
我不是要把他的枕头弄蓬
I'm not plumping his pillows here.
要把他摆成头低脚高仰卧位
I'm putting him in the/trendelenburg position,
让气泡到他心脏顶端去/好把泡泡给吸出来
move the bubble to the apex of/his heart so you can suck it out.
把那该死的注射器拿来
Now,get the damn syringe.
我不能让你冒险去戳他的心脏/去找什么子虚乌有的气泡
I can't risk you stabbing him in the heart/looking for an unconfirmed air bubble.
戳
Stab him.
Hadley大夫!
Dr. Hadley!
看吧 她都不知道你叫什么
See? She doesn't even know your name.
朝他心口上戳啊!
Stab his heart!
血氧饱和度75
Stats at 75--
是啊 他要窒息了
yes. He's suffocating.
- 你要是错了.../- 闭嘴做决定
- If you're wrong--/- shut up and make a decision.
杵那儿 他一样死路一条
Keep standing there,he's/dead either way.
Hadley大夫!
Dr.hadley!
抱歉
I'm sorry.
把门打开
open the door
别开枪!
Don't shoot!
把他送手术室去
Get him to the O.R.
氧和度上去了
The o2 sats.
是个气泡
It was an air bubble.
他没事了
He's okay.
别的护士都会帮我塞好被角的
The other nurse/always used to tuck me in.
我在外面的躺椅上...
I'll be on the couch...
腿上还会放一把枪
with a shot gun in my lap.
担心我有危险?
Worrying about me?
以防你一瘸一拐地溜出边境
Making sure you don't try and/make a limp for the border.
好好睡一觉吧
Get some sleep.
我睡不着 妈咪
I'm not sleepy,mommy.
我也是
Me neither.
你是谁?
Who are you?
为什么要跟踪我?
And why are you stalking me?
客观来讲 是你在跟踪我
Technically,you're stalking me.
这是什么?
What is that?
蚊子?
Mosquito?
也许是只苍蝇
Maybe just a fly.
膏油里面的苍蝇/(比喻美中不足)
In the ointment.
那么说 肯定有什么搞错了
So there's something wrong.
我忽略了某个细节/以致得出了整个错误的结论
There's some detail I'm not noticing/that's spoiling the big picture.
这是个...重要提示?
Is this...significant?
还是说这个梦境将要往/一个截然不同的方向发展?
Or is this dream just going in/a different direction now?
我想 这取决于...
I guess that depends.
你想用它干什么?
What are you going to do with that?
我要用这个替你包扎
I have to tie this around you.
我很冷
I'm cold.
坚持下去
Stay with me.
我为什么这么说?
Why did I say that?
嘿
Hey.
走开
Oh,go away.
还没有结束
It's not over.
我救错人了
I saved the wrong person.
这并非梦境或幻觉/或是药物引致的仙境梦游
this wasn't just a dream or a fantasy/or a drug-induced trip to wonderland.
你是说 那个有气泡的司机/只是一个巧合?
So the bus driver with the air/bubble's just a coincidence?
不 我把前因后果反过来了
No. I got the causation flipped.
不是气泡导致了车祸
Bubble didn't cause the crash.
而是车祸引起了气泡移位
Crash caused the bubble to dislodge.
没有出现四肢抽搐的症状
There was no myoclonic jerk.
而是我在别的人身上看到了别的东西
I saw something else in someone else.
你不能走
You're not leaving.
对一个脑子接近崩溃边缘的病人来说
What's the most dangerous thing/a patient could do
最危险的行为是什么?
when his brain is on the/brink of herniating?
提高心率 血压--/所以你要好好歇一下
Elevated heart rate,bp-- which/is exactly why you need to stop.
我不能睡 我要在房子里踱上几圈/破解我看所到的片断的含义
Instead of sleeping,I'm going to be pacing around/this apartment,trying to decipher those visions.
为什么这对你如此重要?
Why does this matter so much?
我不知道
I don't know.
心率多少?
Heart rate?
心率127
127.
血压呢?
Bp?
情景式记忆
Contextual memory.
我要和全部31个乘客一起回到巴士上/才能回忆起我看到谁 发生了什么事
I need to get back on that bus with all 31/passengers to remember who and what I saw.
我不会替你把车祸受害人找来的/因为你已经不清醒了
I'm not gonna call in crash/victims because you've gone insane.
也许 我并不需要真正的受害人
Maybe I don't need the actual victims.
谁演Anne Mckeehan?
Who's playing anne mckeehan?
你在这
Right here.
送去普林斯顿综合医院的无名女2号
Jane doe number two/from princeton general.
你在这
Right here.
你也是 没错
You too,that's right.
摇滚男
Goth kid.
你们 去右后方
Yeah. At the back on the right.
没错 这儿
Yeah. Here.
好了
Okay.
你觉得盯着我们T恤上的照片/会比催眠更有效吗?
you think that staring at pictures on our/shirts is gonna be more effective than hypnosis?
只要你别吭声就行了
Well,if you'd only stop talking,
情景再现可以刺激我海马体/和海马旁回的活动
the reenactment could stimulate activity in/my hippocampus and parahippocampal cortex.
我们要在这里坐多久/你才会被刺激起来?
how long do we have to sit/here before you are stimulated?
别盯着我的胸部看
Stop staring at my breasts.
也别说没有看头
And don't say,"or lack thereof."
你没事吧?
You okay?
你看到了什么?
What do you see?
只是...走了一下神
Just...slipped away.
这是维可丁吗?
Is that vicodin?
不 是提高记忆力的醒脑剂
No. Just a/little memory pick-me-up.
毒扁豆碱
Physostigmine.
你疯了吗?
are you crazy?
治疗老年痴呆的药物会让你的脑子超负荷运行
Alzheimer drugs will make your/brain go into overdrive.
这正是我的目的所在
That's the point.
它可以加速神经元活动/提高我的记忆动力
It'll speed up my neuronal firing,turn/up the voltage on my memory.
还有搞垮你的心脏
and blow out your heart.
你到底吃了多少?
How many did you take?
你是指刚刚呢 还是包括一路上吃的?
Just now,or including the/ones I took on the ride over?
House 这不值得...
house,this isn't worth...
House?
house?
为什么你会在这里?
Why are you here?
你相信有理由可以解释一切
You believe in reason above all else.
一定存在这么一个理由
There must be a reason.
你有事情要告诉我
You have something to tell me.
是的
Yes.
我是谁?
Who am I?
你这是在问我 不是告诉我
That's asking,not telling.
你是谁?
Who are you?
你知道我是谁
You know who I am.
要是我知道的话 早就躺在床上了/而不是在第六大道上拼命吃毒扁豆碱
If I did,I'd be passed out in bed instead of/oding on physostigmine on the 6th street cross-town.
我的项链是用什么做的?
What's my necklace made of?
树脂
Resin.
我是谁?
Who am I?
我不知道
I don't know.
为什么要让我猜?
Why the guessing game?
因为你不知道答案
Because you don't know the answer.
如果说 我不知道 你也不知道
If I don't,you don'T.
但你知道提示所在
You know the clues.
我知道什么能唤醒你的潜意识
I know what's bugging your subconscious.
我的项链是用什么做的?
What's my necklace made of?
不
No.
我是谁?
Who am I?
不可能
Doesn't make sense.
我的项链是用什么做的?
What's my necklace made of?
Amber(琥珀)
Amber.
我要用这个替你包扎
I have to...tie this around you.
我很冷
I'm cold.
坚持下去
Stay with me.
Just stay with me.
先生 你没事吧?
Sir,are you all right?
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
你哪里伤着了吗?
Are you injured anywhere?
他们在那边会照顾你的
They'll take care of you over there.
他回过气来了
He's coming out of it.
脉搏很强
strong pulse.
你这个白痴!
You idiot!
你停止了心跳
Your heart stopped.
Amber
Amber.
什么?
What?
Amber
Amber.
那个人是Amber
It was amber.
她当时在巴士上
She was on the bus.
你几乎把自己害死了/只得出一个磕药磕昏了头的幻觉?
You almost kill yourself,and all/we're gettingis drug-induced fantasies.
你联系过她没有?
Have you spoken to her?
她这会儿可能在上班
She's probably working.
她一直在值班
She's--she's been on-call.
我打给她了...
I called her...
她没有打回...
she didn't call--
她怎么会...
I-I-- how could she...
我不知道
I don't know.
无名女2号
Jane doe number two.
"女性 年近30 肾脏损伤"
"Female,late 20s,kidney damage."
Amber的右肩胛上是不是有个胎记?
Does amber have a birthmark on/her right shoulder blade?
她当时在车上和我一起
She was on the bus with me.
她就是那个快死的人
She's the one who's dying.